<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CritCat.org</title><link>critcat.org/</link><description>Recent content on CritCat.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 21:08:01 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="critcat.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Provenance</title><link>critcat.org/provenance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 07:39:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>critcat.org/provenance/</guid><description>This resource would not exist if it were not for the following individuals, resources, and communities, who I am very grateful to/wards:
The folks that I am the most indebeted to are those who introduced me to these conversations:
Emily Drabinski, whose article Queering the Catalog: Queer Theory and the Politics of Correction initally introduced me to this work and ideas.
Emily&amp;rsquo;s article on Teaching the Radical Catalog is a fantastic resource.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>critcat.org/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 10:05:49 +1000</pubDate><guid>critcat.org/about/</guid><description>Bri Watson B.M. (&amp;ldquo;Bri&amp;rdquo;) Watson is a white queer crip &amp;amp; nonbinary settler living in Tsleil-Waututh. They are a PhD. student at the University of British Columbia&amp;rsquo;s iSchool where they focus on focusing on queer nomenclature, histories of information, and equitable cataloging in GLAMS (galleries, archives, libraries, museums, and special collections). Additionally, they are the Director of HistSex.com, a free and open access resource for the history of sexuality. They serve as the Archivist-Historian of the Consensual Non-Monogamies Taskforce of the American Psychological Association and contribute to Homosaurus, an international linked data vocabulary for LGBTQ terms.</description></item><item><title>Definitions</title><link>critcat.org/definitions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 14:27:13 +1000</pubDate><guid>critcat.org/definitions/</guid><description>Confused about terms? This page a work in progress&amp;hellip;
Glossary CritCat is short for “critical cataloging,” a movement of cultural heritage workers who work to bring social justice, radical empathy, and outreach work into their everyday practice. Recognizing the need for information maintenence and care, critical catalogers read cataloging and classification systems with an eye for catalogic warrant, reflecting on the potential harm or benefit of each term on the catalog, users, and the library community as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>critcat.org/contact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:49:50 +1000</pubDate><guid>critcat.org/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>critcat.org/resources/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 07:39:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>critcat.org/resources/</guid><description>Zotero Database It is highly recommended that you use the Zotero.org version, as that has better formatting and includes sorting options. If that is not an option, there is an automatically-generated list below.
The main library is divided up into 16 categories/subfolders based on the type of critique or focus they offer. Individual articles can &amp;amp; do belong to multiple categories. All tags on articles are automatically generated and do not reflect the author&amp;rsquo;s view.</description></item></channel></rss>